adonline.id.au 2019-03-04

# Privacy Statement | Adam Dimech Online

This privacy statement has been prepared in order that this website’s users may understand what happens to their information if they submit content or otherwise interact with this website.

## Applicability of Policy

For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, all pages and online images appearing on adonline.id.au (or any subdomain thereof), adamdimech.com, adamdime.ch and photologium.com are described as “Adam Dimech Online materials” and the sites collectively referred to as “Adam Dimech Online”.

## Purpose of Policy

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to tell you what kind of information may be gathered about you when you visit this site, how that information may be used, whether it’s disclosed it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding the use of, and your ability to correct this information. The policy allows you to choose what kind and how much information you provide to Adam Dimech and Adam Dimech Online and to control how any information you provide is used. Adam Dimech Online’s goal is to provide you with a satisfying experience while allowing you to control your privacy and to give you a means to voice any questions or concerns you may have.

This policy applies only to Adam Dimech Online and not to other companies’ or organisations’ websites to which Adam Dimech Online is linked.

## Collection of Information

Information is collected from you primarily to make it easier and more rewarding for you to use Adam Dimech Online. Depending on the service you are accessing, you may be asked to provide information such as your name, email address or other information. It is entirely your choice whether you respond to these questions or not.

Adam Dimech Online collects two types of information. The first type is anonymous information. For instance, the Adam Dimech Online server (adonline.id.au or photologium.com) collects data which indicates your computer’s country of origin (eg: .au for Australia), your IP address (your computer’s identity), the type of browser you are using, the duration of your visit and the pages you download. None of this can be related to you personally, and you remain totally anonymous.

The second type of information that Adam Dimech Online collects is personal information. Adam Dimech Online will collect personal information that makes known the specifics of who you are such as your name, email address, or postal address, when you willingly provide it. With this information, Adam Dimech Online can provide a variety of enhanced services that are not available to anonymous users.

On rare occasions, Adam Dimech Online may specifically ask for personal information about you when you sign up to use a service. Certain information may be required, such as your name, age, internet address or screen name, residential address and/or type of computer in order to provide that service or product to you. This information may also be used to inform you of additional services which may interest you. You can choose not to receive such information when you are undertaking product or service registration on the Adam Dimech Online website. How much of your personal information that you choose to disclose to Adam Dimech Online is completely up to you. The only way we know something about you personally is if you provide it.

## Use of Anonymous Information

Adam Dimech Online automatically gathers anonymous information to monitor the use of Adam Dimech Online like the numbers and frequency of visitors to Adam Dimech Online and its areas. Adam Dimech Online only uses such data in the aggregate. This collective data helps Adam Dimech determine how many visitors use parts of the site, so improvements can be made to Adam Dimech Online to assure that it is as appealing as possible for as many users as possible. Adam Dimech will never publish this information. It is solely used by the site administrator to monitor the site's popularity.

## Use of Personal Information

Adam Dimech will only use the personal information you have chosen to provide for the purpose for which you provided it. Adam Dimech will not use it for any other purpose without your consent.

## Cookies

Cookies may be used by Adam Dimech Online

## Disclosure

There will be occasions where it will be necessary for Adam Dimech to disclose your personal information to third parties. Adam Dimech may be required by law to disclose the information, or Adam Dimech may be required to disclose your personal information to third parties to provide the service you have requested. However, the disclosure will only be made where it is necessary to fulfil the purpose for which you disclosed your personal information. Otherwise than stated above, Adam Dimech does not disclose personal information that you provide, such as your name, address, email address or telephone number, to any organisation or person outside Adam Dimech Online unless you have authorised us to do so. For example, when you contribute to an online forum you may want to publish your name and email address.

## No Sale of Personal Information

Under no circumstances will Adam Dimech Online sell or receive payment for licensing or disclosing your personal information.

## Interacting with Adam Dimech Online

When interacting with Adam Dimech Online, it is suggested that you use your discretion and exercise caution when providing your personal information.

Note that whenever you post personal information in publicly accessible places, such as chat rooms or message boards, this information becomes available to anyone with access to the internet. This information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Therefore, it is recommended that you refrain from posting any information that you do not want seen in these public areas. For example, when participating in an Adam Dimech Online forum, guest book or chat area, your name will appear on the message board. If you do not want your real name to appear use a false name but do not under any circumstances use somebody else’s name.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any personal information. Be responsible whenever you are online.

## Access and Correction: Personal Data

If Adam Dimech holds your personal information Adam Dimech will, where possible, provide you with access to the information. 

Adam Dimech will take reasonable steps to correct the information so that it is accurate, complete and up to date. Under most circumstances, this will be stored on servers as emails. Information will be erased after a period of time if Adam Dimech determines that there is no need to retain it.

## Complaints about Privacy

If you have any complaints relating to online privacy issues on our websites, please notify Adam Dimech via the [Adam Dimech Online Feedback Form](https://www.adonline.id.au/contact/). While Adam Dimech Online accepts no liability for any material or links posted to the service, all complaints will be investigated.

## Changes to Adam Dimech Online privacy policy

As of 7 July 2007, this Privacy Policy was extended to include services provided by photologium.com.

## Services

This Privacy Policy is designed to accommodate growth in the size and number of services offered by Adam Dimech Online. This policy makes mention of guest books, forums, panels and other services which may or may not be offered at any particular time. This policy applies to emails sent to any address hosted by adonline.id.au or photologium.com.
